learner.org 2018-05-31

# Annenberg Learner: Privacy Policy

| 

Privacy Policy 

**Your Privacy**  
Revised: July 10, 2014

Annenberg Learner wishes to protect your privacy on the Web and in all areas where we connect with you. This privacy statement applies to all Annenberg Learner websites, mobile applications and other related online services. It is divided into two parts: first, our general principles, and, second, the detailed actions we take to behave according to those principles. You can think of this second section as the "small print" or "legalese" section. Please feel free to send any questions you may have about this privacy policy to us at [info@learner.org](mailto:info@learner.org).

**Our Principles**

**1\. Your privacy will be protected.**

> Annenberg Learner shares some information we receive about you with trusted third parties. Each such party must agree to use reasonable security procedures and practices, appropriate to the nature of the information involved, in order to protect your information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. . This information includes both traditional factual information (your name, address, phone number, etc.) and electronic, technical, Web-oriented information (your IP address, email configuration, email address, etc.) Neither we, nor these third parties, will use this information for any reason except to analyze aggregate usage patterns for the site; and to provide and maintain services you have requested through learner.org.
> 
> We may also share information with businesses controlling, controlled by, or under common control with Annenberg Learner. If Annenberg Learner is merged, acquired, or sold, or in the event of a transfer of some or all of our assets, we may disclose or transfer information in connection with such transaction. You will have the opportunity to opt out of any such transfer if, in our discretion, the new entity plans to handle your information in a way that differs materially from this Privacy Policy. 

**2\. We do not share mailing lists.**

> Annenberg Learner does not sell or exchange mailing lists. 

**3\. You will not be spammed.**

> You will only receive email outreach messages from us if you register as a workshop leader, make an inquiry about our work, or request to be placed on a list receiving weekly or monthly updates and news from us through email. 

**4\. We will address your privacy concerns promptly.**

> If you receive our weekly or monthly email news in error, or if you ever wish to discontinue them, or if any other concern related to online interactivity or online ordering arises, please let us know immediately-and we will work hard to solve the problem promptly. 

**Our Actions**

The electronic information our servers collect about visitors depends on what the visitors do while visiting our Web site. 

**1\. If you visit our site to browse, read, download information, or make an order:**

> We collect the IP ("internet protocol") addresses of our site visitors, in order to measure the number and frequency of visitors. This is often referred to as collecting information about "traffic."
> 
> We use cookies on our site to facilitate the purchase of products, viewing of videos, interaction with various Web site forms, and the general user experience on our Web site. If you do not wish to accept cookies from our Web site, you can set your Web browser to block the cookies, but this may impact your use of the Web site. 

**2\. If you identify yourself personally to us by sending us an email or using an online form to order materials, to register as a workshop site leader, or to subscribe to any of our weekly or monthly email news updates:**

> We store the information you voluntarily provide, and use it to contact you for matters related to the purpose for which you gave it to us. We do not share this information with other organizations or use it for commercial purposes other than those you directly request. If you sign up as a workshop site leader, we may give your work address and email to individual workshop participants who wish to join your site or share your resources.
> 
> In other limited and exceptional circumstances, we may be required by law to disclose the information you submit. An investigation of credit card fraud would be an example of such circumstances.
> 
> If you use one of our online forms, the information you provide is entirely at your discretion. In the event of a complaint or request from you in the future, it may be impossible for us to refer to, respond to, or investigate your complaint unless you have already shared some information with us through one of our online forms. In other words, if you visit our site anonymously, and leave no footprints behind, we won't be able to help you by retracing any of your steps. 

**3\. We may collect personal, passive information for research purposes.**

> **Passive Data Collection.** We may receive passively-collected information through a variety of methods including but not limited to:
> 
> **Cookies and Web Beacons.** We may use a variety of methods, including "cookies" and "Web beacons," to collect information. A cookie is a small data file that is transferred to an Internet user's browser by a web server. Cookies are designed to store basic information, such as a user's preferences. A Web beacon (sometimes referred to as a "clear GIF") is a small string of code placed in a web page, email message (such as the Annenberg Learner newsletter) or other media format in order to gather statistical usage information.
> 
> The information that we collect with cookies, Web beacons, and other passive methods may include your IP address, information about how you interact with advertisements and other content, browser type, system type, device type, the content and pages that you access, the date and time you view pages, and the page from which you navigated.
> 
> **Click-through URLs.** In some of our email messages, we may use a "click-through URL" linked to content on a website. When you click one of these URLs, you pass through a separate web server before arriving at the destination page. We track this click-through data to help us determine interest in particular topics and measure the effectiveness of our customer communications. If you prefer not to be tracked in this way, you should not click text or graphic links in the email messages.
> 
> **Location-Based Services.** We may collect, use, and share (with Annenberg Foundation partners, service providers and licensees) precise location data, including the real-time location of your mobile or fixed location device. We will only share this information to provide you with learner.org and services requested by you. We may also aggregate this information in a way that does not identify an individual user.
> 
> **Analytics Tools.** Learner.org uses Google Analytics, a Web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses "cookies," which are text files placed on your computer, as well as other technology, to help learner.org analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of learner.org (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google. Learner.org uses Google Analytics for the purpose of evaluating your use of learner.org, compiling reports on learner.org activity for Web site operators and providing other services relating to learner.org activity and Internet usage. For information about how Google will use your information, please visit <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/>. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser; however, please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use the full functionality of learner.org. By using learner.org, you consent to the processing of data about you by learner.org and Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.
> 
> **Online Tracking.** Our systems do not recognize browser "Do Not Track" signals, but several of our service providers who utilize tracking cookies or web beacons on learner.org enable you to opt out of targeted advertising practices. To learn more about targeted advertising practices or to opt out of this type of advertising, you can visit www.networkadvertising.org or www.aboutads.info/choices/. We also provide you with additional tools to opt out of marketing from us. You can learn about this below in Section 4 of this Privacy Policy.
> 
> **Children under 18.** We do not knowingly seek or collect personal information from users under the age of 18. If we determine we have inadvertently gathered personal information from a user under the age of 18, we will promptly delete any and all such personal information from our records. 

**4\. If you want to retrieve or correct your personal information that may be in our records:**

> Upon request we will provide you with access to your contact information (e.g., name, address, phone number), and offer you the chance to correct inaccuracies.
> 
> When you use the Journey North App, you will be given the opportunity to allow us to provide the personal location of your mobile device and e-mail address. The location and email information are going to be used to interface with the geo-tagging of the "My Sightings" part of the mobile app. 

**5\. If you would like to opt out of our mailings and services:**

> If you do not want to receive marketing email or postal mail from us in the future, please let us know and we will comply. Give us the exact email or postal mail address you would like removed from our marketing and newsletter lists, and we will do it. 

**6\. Security:**

> It is our intent to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of information that we have collected from you. We employ reasonable security measures to protect the security of the information you submit to us. We limit the information we provide to outside companies with whom we contract to only what they need to carry out their responsibilities. When you request product information or create an account on the Site, your transactional information is transmitted in an encrypted format. We maintain the data you provide, along with a record of your purchases, in a secured database. We cannot however guarantee the security of user account information and other personally information at all times. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, accidental disclosure and other factors may compromise the security of user information at any time.
> 
> If you send us an email message or use one of our online forms, you should be aware that your information is not necessarily secure against electronic interception by unknown and unforeseeable third parties, commonly known as "hackers." If you believe your communication to us includes sensitive information, please contact us by postal mail or telephone rather than by email. 

**7\. In the event of changes to this policy:**

> We reserve the right to use site visitor information in the future for new, unanticipated uses not disclosed in this privacy notice. This is not because we foresee any change in our principles, but because ongoing advances in electronic interactivity may change the very ways you and we connect. Such changes are impossible to foresee. In any case, if our electronic information practices change in these ways, we will post such policy changes on our Web site. Those changes will go into effect on the "Revised" date shown in the revised Privacy Policy. By continuing to learner.org, you consent to the revised Privacy Policy. You will then have, as you do now, the ability to opt out of these new uses. If you are concerned about how your information is used, check back at our Web site periodically. 

**7\. How to contact us:**

> By postal mail: 
>
>> Annenberg Learner  
>  1301 Pennsylvania Avenue NW #302  
>  Washington, DC 20004
> 
> By telephone: 
>
>> 1-202-783-0500 
> 
> By email: 
>
>> [info@learner.org](mailto:info@learner.org) (for general issues)  
>  [order@learner.org](mailto:order@learner.org) (for questions related to an online order you have placed) 
>> 
>> If you are unsure which email address to use, please use [info@learner.org](mailto:info@learner.org).  
  
---|---
